hello everybody and welcome to our for
industry market or series now in this
video again we're not gonna be going too
much into scripting and I do apologize
for guys who want to really get into the
more advanced stuff but I just need to
make sure that people who are new
understand the these fundamental things
so in this video I'm gonna explain some
things about data types now we're in in
my lure tutorial series if you've ever
watched it we went over some data types
and some of those were pools numbers
strings you know there was a few data
types like their tables now in Garry's
Mod we're gonna be using more of these
and some of these will include player
data types entity data types let's go
over some more meta data or meta tables
as well that's just a few there will be
a lot more um so what I'm gonna do here
is I'm gonna go ahead and bring up the
wiki for Garry's Mod now on the wiki if
you go to classes here you can see all
of the different basically data types or
classes that we're gonna be working with
and you can see player is one of them
now I don't expect you to be using all
of these but fundamental ones like
player and entities are ones that we're
gonna be using so when when I'm storing
something in a variable like if I did
something like test is equal to local
play which again doesn't make sense to
you now but well soon you may be
wondering well what this test hold does
it hold the number does it hold the
string does it hold the pool well no it
holds the metadata for the player now as
I said there is a few of these we will
be going over them and yeah so I just
wanted to make sure that you understand
that when I refer to playa de Ayer or
NPC Day or anything like that that's
what we're gonna be referring to again I
apologize a short video but in the next
one we should actually be getting
started on some code in and running some
functions so I hope you enjoyed the
video I hope you learned something and
I'll see you in the next video thanks
for watching
you