hello everybody and welcome to part five
in this gym I'll do a tutorial series
now before we get started I do want to
apologize for the lack of videos I have
not been feeling too well my mixer broke
meaning of my mic quality was just
appalling and again I really really
apologize for it but nevertheless let's
get started so in this video we're gonna
be taking a look at running functions on
the player which is important for two
reasons one is because we need to
understand how we can execute Mehta
functions on different data types but on
top of that we also need to understand
how we can get references to players in
different situations so what we're gonna
do we're gonna stop a single player
world if you have not done so already I
recommend you do so now then what we're
gonna do is we're gonna open up sublime
and that Lua file that is in our Garry's
Mod directory if you guys remember it
from the previous video I think so
anyway we're gonna go ahead we're gonna
get rid of that and we're gonna get
started so if you remember before well
actually we're get started first how do
we get a reference to the player so I'm
gonna open up the gmod wiki and I'm
gonna go ahead and search local whoops
local player and as you can see on the
global there's a function here called
local player now you know it's it's
orange which means you can only run on
the client and the description says that
it returns to place object of the
current client local player will return
no until all entities have been
initialized so this part we don't need
to worry about for now but this part is
important it returns to players object
yet the player object of the current
client so what that means is it will
return the player object itself in the
physical world and then we can do
whatever we want to it so what we're
gonna do is I'm gonna make a local
variable call it PRI and I'm gonna set
it equal to local player and I'm gonna
call that and I do have to call it as a
function let me go ahead and change this
to G mother there we go I do have to set
as a function because that's what it is
and now the variable PR y then source of
reference to this so just a just a
double check I'm gonna do lua underscore
whoops newer underscore open script and
score CL now you're gonna want to make
sure that you run this on the client
because local player will not work on
the server as we've seen it's a client
only function so when we run this as you
can see we've got no errors so things
are good
what can we do with this well let's go
ahead and go back to the gmod wiki and
search player if you search whoopsie
player right and then we're gonna go
into the classes section here and you'll
see all of these player : and then a ton
of these functions right so let's go
have a look at alive now this is blue
and orange which means it can be used on
both client and server now it checks if
the player is alive and will return a
boolean which is true or false of
whether the player is alive or not so
now let's say we go back in here we're
gonna go ahead and print well first of
all we're gonna make available I'm gonna
call it is a player alive now the way
how we call these functions is kind of
exactly what they look like here player
would be our reference to the player
then we do : and we call the function on
the player so in this case we can do PR
y : alive now remember that PR y is our
reference to our local player and what
we're gonna do is we're gonna check if
it's alive we're gonna store the value
that it returns inside of this is player
alive
and we're simply gonna go ahead and
we're gonna print out is player alive I
do apologize for that couch in let me
zoom out a bit hey guys so now if I go
back into my game and I run the script
as you can see it prints out true but if
I go ahead and kill myself and I rerun
that's good it now prints out false
because I am no longer alive so I hope
you understand that but on top of that
there is many many many things we can do
and in case you didn't notice at the
wiki there is a lot of things here so
let's go ahead and look at a few other
one so now the one set of blue for
example kill kill can only be called as
it says here can only be called because
it's blue on the server which means that
on the client you cannot kill anybody
from the client you can ask the server
to kill people but we'll get into that
on another date so let's go ahead and
take a look at some more some of these
being like the orange one we can take a
look at is speaking
and that is gonna return to a fault of
whether the play was speaking we got set
muted which would mute a never player on
the server so as long as you had this
would be the the other play on the
server then you could have a reference
to them set them to meet it and set to
meet it to true but yeah we're gonna go
ahead and take a look at Frank's
so basically frags is kills and as you
can see my Frank's right now is going to
be zero because on the scoreboard wait
my fact is negative one actually because
I killed myself but we'll go ahead and
we'll store frags in there instead of
we'll just name this two kills and let's
go ahead and simply print that out now
let's go ahead and run our script and as
you can see it prints out negative one
but let's say I go to the NPC section
here and I just couldn't go to a weapon
and grab something now all of these are
obviously account if it kills and as you
can see oops on the scoreboard I oh I
guess not
I thought that the NPC's Candida skills
but clearly not so I'm still gonna be on
negative one but what we can do is we
can also get my deaths now I know this
may seem a bit repetitive but I'm just
trying to make sure that you understand
the point of this now as you can see
I've died once I do it again I've died
two times and I couldn't die again for
whoops I can die no I've got it there we
go
I can die again for the third time now I
hope this makes sense but yeah and the
actually will do it this video you guys
seem to like longer videos so we'll do
this one so now we can do that actually
nest now I do I do apologize I will
leave that to the next video because it
is gonna be a little longer but yeah I
hope you guys learn something I hope you
understood some some stuff but yeah
that's how we can execute information on
the player now retrieving a specific
player on the server is different which
is why we haven't gone into the server
side yet but for the client you can get
the the client player which is the the
person's game who it is you can get
their client their player
and we store it in the variable player
which is our reference to it and then we
call on that variable the function depth
which will return the number of deaths
that players had then we simply go ahead
and we print that out so I hope that
makes sense to you in the next video
we'll go ahead and we'll do a little bit
more complicated again and I do
apologize for those of you who find this
series very simple it will grow very
fine complexity but to begin with for
people who are new they've got to
understand these basics and and even
though you may think I'm never gonna use
this in my script you will they are the
fundamentals of coding for gmod so again
I hope you learned something and I will
see you all in the next video hope you
enjoyed it
you