hello everybody and welcome to part 6
now industry module stories now if you
remember in the previous video we
learned about how we can get a reference
to the local player and how we can run
functions on those players now we can
also do the same for entities so now
we'll go ahead and we'll bring up our
Garry's Mod and we'll also bring up our
sublime now if you remember in the
previous tutorial we could do local
player and that would be our reference
to the local play all right well we can
do end stuff get all and that would give
us a table and if you don't know what a
table is go back and check previous
videos it would give us a table of every
single entity that exists currently in
the world now this will include players
props map objects you know all kind of
things like that but how is that useful
well we'll go ahead and I'm gonna write
a quick script now this wouldn't work in
theory but I'll show you it real quick
so what we can do is we can make a
variable and call it entities I am and
we can certainly go to and stock get
four now that's gonna get a list of our
table sorry of all of the entities that
exist on the server now what we can do
is if you remember in our other videos
about loops we can simply use for
kayvyun pairs to loop over that and
we're gonna loop over the table entities
because remember tenth entities is a
table of data from from the end stock at
all function so again if you don't know
what kV and paise means go back and
check my lure tutorial series I can't
remember the exact number I think it's
number four and I cover tables there and
if you check the other one there will be
a tutorial to on how to do loops like
this but anyway then what we can do is
we can go like yeah bring up the the
gmod wiki real quick over here and yeah
we can go ahead and we can search now
set color okay and as you can see here
it says entity : set color so if you
remember before when we seen a function
it says player : set color now player is
because it wanted player data while in
case we're gonna use it on an entity it
wants an entity data and you'll see that
it's gonna ask for a table of color I'll
explain that in a minute but what we can
do is V is gonna be the value in that
table which in this case will be the
current entity that we've looped over
and I'm gonna call : set color because I
can call set color on an entity now up
here I make a local variable call it C
which is short for color and we can
assign it a color the way how we can do
that is we type the function color and
then we type in some parameters now in
this case we'll do 255 255 255 that's
gonna be white now if you're not too
sure if I quickly open up photoshop over
here once it loads I do apologize there
we go if you're unsure if you just go
into well that was like it if you just
go into Photoshop you could make any
color you want over here right and then
as you can see here there is an Archie
and a B value all right now are being
red green G being queen and BB and blue
now this year primary colors I'm with
these you can make any color you could
possibly imagine
so let's say we wanted a red we could go
red and as you can see it red is 255
green is 0 blue is 0 so we can use that
so let's say I want to make the color
red I could do to 5500 right so then I
create that color I stored in C and then
the color I set it to is whoops is C now
the reason why I do this is because as
you can see here it asks for a color now
I know it asked for a table but by table
it means this color property and there
we have it so that's that now we go
ahead and we set its color so let's go
let's go in-game let's spawn in a few
props real quick just like this and as
you can see we now have a nice line of
props now I'm gonna go lure underscore
open script CL and I'm gonna open up our
test script and now as you can see some
of them changed back to white I'll
explain why in a minute but as you can
see pretty much all of them turn red and
this includes map entities too so you
can see how they you could have the
lights have gone and also if I go ahead
and no clip now over into the color room
oh not that kind of um didn't update my
bad but you can see how they change and
as you can see over time they
actually changed back to the original
color if I run it again they change but
soon as I interact with them they go
back to the normal color now
I'll quickly give you an explanation of
why this is and this is because set
color even though it can be called on
client and server it should only be
called on the server and what it'll do
is it'll set some set of props color to
that color set a props color to that
color yes sorry my bad now the problem
is is we're doing this client-side on
the client we're changing it only for
our game not the actual service so it
only visually looks different for us not
anybody else on the server and as soon
as a prop updates such as moving or gets
replaced or anything changes on it the
server then reuptake the client with the
new information that includes the color
so the color goes back to its original
color as soon as it's interacted or
moved so I hope that makes sense so
that's how we can run functions on an
entity now I know this doesn't seem like
much all we did is change your color of
an entity that doesn't even work
correctly but in the next video we're
gonna be showing you or I'm gonna be
showing you how we can execute
server-side scripts we're gonna be
moving slightly over to the server we're
still mainly focused on the client right
now but we can show you some stuff on
the server now the reason why this is is
because if we go ahead and look at these
as you can see the majority of the the
cool ones if you go to the wiki yourself
a server only functions so we gotta get
our script running on the server so yeah
so I'll see you in the next video I hope
you learned something the next video
should be pretty soon if you have any
questions feel free to leave a comment
and I'll I'll see you in the next video
you