hello everybody and welcome to part two
in this gmod people do it saucers now in
this video again we're not gonna be
learning too much but what we will be
doing is we will be showing you how to
basically run a script inside of Garry's
Mod so what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna go
ahead and I will open up sublime I'm
gonna go to file new file just like
normal
remember based on whichever text editor
you're using this may be different but
normally it's the same for all I'm just
gonna go ahead and hit ctrl s to save
I'm then gonna go over to where garry's
mod is installed steam library steam
apps common Garry's Mod then go to
Garry's Mod again and then go ahead and
go into newer sorry and then here is
where you're gonna want to save it so
for example I'm just gonna save this as
test dot lower now remember it's got to
be a Lua file so if we go ahead and say
that now you can get the gmod low Alexa
which is done by F jpg I remember his
name there will be a link in the
description to that that's if you're
using sublime but I know there is also
one for Adam and notepad plus plus so if
you using even one of those it will also
work now in here we're gonna write our
script I was good it's gonna be very
simple it's just gonna simply be print
hello world just like that now you'll
notice how we don't have the i/o dot
read on here which we did in my lure
tutorial series and that's because
Garry's Mod is is running this as the
environment meaning if our script gets
to the end of the code Garry's Mod it's
still gonna be running so it doesn't
close so IO doc read it's not needed
anymore just simply print hello world so
let's then go into a gmod will then
start up a single-player game and once
we're in the game there we go we're
gonna go ahead and we're gonna go into
our console I'm will type Lua and the
score open open script and there's
called CL and then you simply start type
in the name of your script in this case
ours was test a lure we do that we hit
enter and as you can see it says it's
running the script and then it says
hello world so the first thing you'll
notice is that this is now our
so with before we had the e terminal on
Windows this is now our console so yeah
that's pretty much that we can also do
Lua underscore open scripts and instead
of doing an underscore CL we just simply
type open script and type of test and as
you can see it did the exact same except
this time our text was in blue and if
you remember our client and server
tutorial I said the orange was client
and blue was the server so when we went
on our client you'll notice how the text
is orange moving around on the server
our text is blue and as I've already
stated in that video there is a client
and server even though I'm on single
player there is basically a server with
one slot for you to join that is not
hosted on the internet but on your local
game so again there is still a client on
the server now I hope that really makes
sense to you again I know this is
another short video but the idea of this
video is just to give you a name
explanation on how we can go ahead and
write and execute scripts now one thing
to know is that for now we're gonna be
doing all of our work inside of that Lua
folder that I told you to save in now
once we obviously get a bit further on
we're gonna go ahead and we're gonna
convert those into add-ons rather than
having to place them into the newer
folder but yeah I hope you learned
something and again I do apologize for
it be in such a short video these are
just designed to give you the
introductory of what we need to get
started so again if you have any
questions leave a comment I hope you
learned something I hope you enjoyed
watching and I'll see you in the next
video
you