hello everybody and welcome to part 1 in
the gmod Lewis fluorosis now in this
video we're not gonna be doing any
coding we're just gonna be going over
the basics of what client and set-aside
is because they're two very important
things to know before you you actually
start coding for Garry's Mod now even if
you want a code in single-player it's
still vital you know this information
because believe it or not there is still
a client and a server relationship when
you're in a single-player game so we'll
go ahead and I'll open up Photoshop and
try my best to explain this so imagine
that this here so the way how server and
client are represented with orange and
blue so this circle here this is the
server ok now the server is what handles
pretty much every every aspect of
gameplay in a server such as when a
player should die dealing damage to a
player update in all of the other
clients on changes and stuff along this
line so this is us ok we are this circle
down here and here is our link to the
server now us as the clients can't do
much in terms of controlling the game as
like I said it's already it's the server
that controls now multiple clients can
be connected to the same server and
let's say
you let's go ahead and just quickly
finish my amazing drawing now this is me
okay this one here now I move slightly
left so on my screen I move a little
left then information is carried across
this connection to the server the server
handles this information moves my player
in the service world and then the server
then goes and updates everybody else on
my new position where I move to now with
certain things that can only be done on
the server and there are certain things
that can only be done on the client okay
now there is a little bit in the middle
called shared which is where things can
be done on both client and server but
mainly you're going to be working in
server to do the majority of the logic
of your programs now when we first up
we're going to be starting in the client
and writing some basic client-side
scripts and once we start to get the
gist of that but I'm going to move over
into the server and once we start to
understand how the server works we're
then going to go ahead and we are going
to work on both of them so we'll find
out how to communicate between those
with your scripts
and how to make something that works
with both people such as say you wanted
to send a message from this player over
to this player how could we do that in
doer and things along that line so I
know this video was short it's just the
basic introductory of you know we're
going to be going now I do want to also
say that if you have not already seen my
Lua tutorial series and you're not
familiar with Lua at all I recommend you
watch that series there will be a link
in the description if you have finished
a series and you're moving on in the
next video we'll be getting into some
coding hopefully some basic scripts but
yeah I hope you understand what I've got
if you don't feel free to leave a
comment and I will get back to you and
thanks for watching see you in the next
video
you